William Anderson III

IT support or project technician, admin, lead

Pierce County, WA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/William-Anderson-III/f26f1881e25476f3

IT services and technologies continue to change IT tremendously every year. Since my first IT job in college, I have experienced working IT from several different perspectives; helpdesk support, project and support team management, DOT.com entrepreneur, and as a contract worker. From old ISA slots to new load balancing switches with QoS, to DOS, Unix, Windows and Apple operating systems; also mobile OSs. My most recent position was as a team lead, and I also work well independently. I am a self-motivated, enjoy coaching and team work. I like the thrill that IT brings with integrating new technologies and mitigating SEV 1 meltdowns. My customer service skills and awareness are also sharp, with our team, other teams and departments, leadership, stakeholders, and office end users My busy mind and body will bring quality results, positive creative vibes, and a proactive and dedicated team player.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Remote IT Technician/ Courier (cw) (security clearance)

Superior Delivery - Tacoma, WA -

January 2015 to Present

- Troubleshoot Kiosk OS and peripherals including wirings, modems, routers, and thermal printers.
- Perform quarterly hardware audits and basic best practices maintenance.
- Collect Kiosk funds and facilitate bank deposits; then provide reports.

IT Project Lead

Starbucks (cw) - Seattle, WA -

January 2017 to November 2017

- •Delegate opportunities and motivate team to continued meeting SLAs for ITSM and projects, performance, and policies to help maintain high level of consistency.
- •Utilized MS Excel, OneNote and Teams to track and document project and for metrics.
- Maintain cohesion between day and night teams. Also ensuring proficiency on proprietary technologies.
- •High frequency of communication within and with other teams, departments, and vendors.
- Organize meetings and trainings on internal and external technologies, culture and expectations.
- •Utilize relevant knowledge and experience of systems (POS, MS hardware and software), customer service, and project management to proactively increase our aptitude, knowledge, and SLA performance levels.
- •Audit project and employee performance. Daily Production Report, Follow-up Report; Slack and E-mail (MS 365) for cooperation evaluation. Also provide project forecasting and reviews.
- •Mitigate problems and issues in part by monitoring ITSM gue though out the day for trouble tickets.
- •Available for round the clock team guidance for unexpected situations.

IT Desktop Technician

Providence Hospital; contract - Olympia, WA -

November 2016 to December 2016

- •Lifecycle swap hundreds of HP thick client desktops and laptops utilizing MS Easy Transfer, Remote Desktop, and solid communication and planning skills.
- •Utilized Microsoft SCCM tool to distribute the majority of the software to clients and update existing ones. (Some examples off software: MS Office, iSite, Kronos, Dragon, and others.
- •Troubleshoot peripherals and software onsite and remotely.

IT Technician

Hard@work Computers - Puyallup, WA -

May 2016 to November 2016

- •Provide PC and network support and trainings for business and residential customers; onsite, remote, and walk-in. All types of hardware (AMD and Intel processors, expansion components/ cards and peripherals, HDD and SSD), software (Windows, MAC, and some mobile OSs).
- •Retrofit donated computers for resale or lease (Certified Microsoft refurbisher). used as temporary replacements for businesses. Repairs or trainings are done remotely using Splashtop RDC or onsite.
- •Onsite wiring and network enhancements. Pulling coaxial and Ethernet cables (both standards) for computers and security system endpoints. Also enhance and creating networks (multiple topologies).

IT Manager

Hollander Hospitality - Seattle, WA -

April 2015 to April 2016

- •Administer 802.3 and .11 LAN networks with Windows servers; Cisco switches, routers; SonicWall firewalls; Elfiq load balancers; Kronos time clocks; thin/thick clients; Oracle Micros POS systems (servers and 3700 POS); and fiber optic backbone. 6 locations utilizing several ISPs (with assigned IP stacks). Managing MS Exchange, SharePoint and other Cloud services were also daily duties.
- •Utilized Kaspersky centralized virus scanning and MS and Citrix for remote access.
- Present concepts to management; IT projects, protocols and polices, PCI and brand specific compliances.
- •Inventory management; hardware, software and licenses. Also managed department budget, inspections, contractors and IT inventory procurement for all departments.
- •Provided end user support for MS Office Suite, shared access and data backups; IHG, Marriott, and Best Western PM systems and NVR & DVR security systems. Consult departments on brand IT standards and implementations.

Owner

ElitePosts.com, Inc - Pierce County, WA; King County, WA; Thurston County, WA -

March 2006 to December 2014

- •Create and inventory products; administer website (Dreamweaver)and e-store (iHost) configuration and maintenance.
- •Utilize MS OS and Office suite for email and administrative duties. Also Intuit QuickBooks.
- •I integrated 3 business models and managed it with almost 10 employees; 3 full time.
- Group and corporate presentations, Advertisements, Promotions, Business Development.
- •Sales, Product manufacturing, Small Field Excavations, Employee Field Management.
- •Recruiting, Training/ Development, Customer problem resolution.

IT Technician

United Parcel Service of America, Inc - Seattle, WA -

March 2001 to August 2005

- •Maintain, workstations, servers, network, and scanning devices; including licensing and inventory.
- Provided internal /external (UPS departments/UPS customers) end user support and trainings. Utilize ticketing system to address and track problem resolution.
- •Support (including configuration) of fiber optics, Ethernet and telecom, MDFs and IDFs locations on multiple topologies. Utilized knowledge networking (802.3) and telecom. Also printers (Zebra 2442/ LPs, Epson, Lexmark), handheld and overhead scanning systems.
- •Perform hardware and software integrations with proprietary and third party solutions (including databases), trainings, upgrades and maintenance.
- •Complete and maintain satisfactory grades on proprietary internal tests (IT standards, company and services) and evaluations.
- •Administer MS Exchange and OSs. Maintain and program Cisco switches. Image systems and maintain corporate hardware.

EDUCATION

BS in IT- Network Administration

Western Governors University - Work at Home

November 2020

AA

Walla Walla Community College - Walla Walla, WA

BS in Management Information Systems

Washington State University - Pullman, WA

LINKS

http://www.linkedin.com/in/wandersonITstorm

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

A+ Certified